Burak Kakillioglu

bkakilli.github.io * Syracuse, NY

Profile

PhD on 3D computer vision with significant image processing and machine learning expertise. Strong personal enthusiasm and professional experience with autonomous robotic systems. A multitude of graduate level software engineering courses alongside with an Electrical Engineering degree (B.S). Notable experience on common DevOps practices, such as Git and Docker. Ability to work on broad range of hardware, OS, software languages and tools. Detailed, dedicated and proactive personality.

Experience

Motorola Solutions Inc., Boston, MA

Jun 2021-Present

Senior Machine Learning Engineer

- Designed and implemented an improved camera tampering detection algorithm on the existing video analytics stack.

Automodality Inc., San Rafael, CA

Nov 2019-May 2020 / Jan 2017-Dec 2017

3D Computer Vision Intern / RA

- Contributed to the development of 3D lidar point cloud segmentation on Jetson TX2 for perception-localization module of aerial asset inspection vehicle
- Developed a 3D localization algorithm using stereo camera for the aerial bridge inspection vehicle

SRI International, Princeton, NJ

May 2019-Aug 2019

3D Computer Vision Intern

- Developed 3D segmentation algorithm for 3D point clouds from lidar and stereo cameras for Automatic Volumetric (Tree) Log Measurement
- Implemented a framework to combine 2D and 3D tree log segmentation
- Implemented the backend of Automatic Log Measurement software

Syracuse University, Syracuse, NY

Aug 2015-May 2021

Research Assistant

- Several algorithms and machine learning models for 3D aerial vehicle vision (PhD Study)
- Microcam (ARPA-E): A system of platforms that detects human presence for substantial improvement in HVAC efficiency
- AirBEM (ARPA-E): An intelligent aerial vehicle platform for auditing thermal deficiencies for building energy retrofits

Education

Syracuse University, Syracuse, NY

Aug 2015-Jul 2021

PhD, Electrical and Computer Engineering, 3.90

Advisor: Senem Velipasalar

Thesis: Computer Vision Applications for Autonomous Aerial Vehicles

Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey

Sept 2011-Jun 2015

BS, Electrical and Electronics Engineering

Technical Skills

- Python, C/C++, MATLAB, Java, C#, web languages, HDL, Assembly
- PyTorch, Tensorflow, Numpy, OpenCV, Open3D, ROS, PCL
- Linux, Windows, OSX, Android
- Jetson, Raspberry Pi, PX4, Arduino (derivatives), FPGA
- Git, Docker, Swarm, Continuous Integration, Full stack web/API development

Honors and Awards

- 2022 All University Doctoral Prize, Syracuse University
- Tuition Scholarship, Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Bilkent University
- 99.9 percentile ranking in the national university entrance exam (YGS)

Selected Publications

- [J1] **B. Kakillioglu**, A. Ren, Y. Wang and S. Velipasalar, "3D Capsule Networks for Object Classification With Weight Pruning," in IEEE Access, vol. 8, pp. 27393-27405, 2020
- [J2] T. Rakha, A. Liberty, A. Gorodetsky, **B. Kakillioglu** and S. Velipasalar, "Heat Mapping Drones: An Autonomous Computer-Vision-Based Procedure for Building Envelope Inspection Using Unmanned Aerial Systems (UAS)," 2018 Technology | Architecture + Design, 2:1, 30-44
- [C1] **B. Kakillioglu**, J. Wang, S. Velipasalar, A. Janani and E. Koch, "3D Sensor-Based UAV Localization for Bridge Inspection," 2019 53rd Asilomar Conference on Signals, Systems, and Computers, Pacific Grove, CA, USA, 2019, pp. 1926-1930.
- [C2] **B. Kakillioglu**, S. Velipasalar, and T. Rakha. "Autonomous heat leakage detection from unmanned aerial vehicle-mounted thermal cameras." In Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Distributed Smart Cameras, pp. 1-6. 2018.
- [C3] **B. Kakillioglu** and S. Velipasalar, "Autonomous altitude measurement and landing area detection for indoor UAV applications," 2016 13th IEEE International Conference on Advanced Video and Signal Based Surveillance (AVSS), Colorado Springs, CO, 2016, pp. 166-172.
- [C4] B. Kakillioglu, K. Ozcan and S. Velipasalar, "Doorway detection for autonomous indoor navigation of unmanned vehicles," 2016 IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP), Phoenix, AZ, 2016, pp. 3837-3841.